ねね　昨日のテレビ見た
Hey, did you see it on TV yesterday?
See what?
何をだ
決まってるじゃないか
You have to ask?
「取材班は見た　浜名湖巨大鰻
"Exposed! The Amazing Truth About Lake Hamana's Giant Eel 'Hassie'!"
ハッシー　驚愕の正体」だよ
Oh, I saw that too!
ああ　それ私も見た
As if there'd be anything like that.
いるわけないだろ　そんなもの
幽霊の正体見たり枯れ尾花ってやつかい　奉太郎
又译疑心生暗鬼，将干枯的芒草错认为是幽灵
"All ghosts are, when the fog lifts, is withered grass in the wind", right?
つまんないやつね
You're so boring.
あんたにはロマンというものがないの
He's about as romantic as a pinch of salt, right, Chi?
ねえ　ちーちゃん
私はいるかいないか　その真実が気になります
I must know the truth of its existence! I can't stop thinking about it!
Well, whether it exists or not, I just hope it's there today.
まあ　いてもいなくてもいいけど　今日はいてほしい気分だね
その方が面白くないかい
That'd be a lot more interesting, right?
幽霊はどれも枯れ尾花さ
Either way, it's just withered grass in the wind, isn't it?
奉太郎らしいや
That's so much like you.
Bored, sitting on the windowsill,
退屈な窓辺に吹き込む風に
I frown at the wind to hide my awkwardness
顔を顰めたのは照れくさ　その裏返し
Hyouka
KamiGami
@ 湮·Molly／小然·酸菜／喵儿·小冷／时末·竭力而为
I nod uncertainly as I shape
曖昧に頷く掌の今日
the future in my hands feeling mighty
描いてる自分は少し大袈裟で
I feel that the wind is bringing change
何かが変わりそうな気がしているよ
I guess that's your fault for calling out to my heart
心に呼びかける君のせいだね
The cloudy sky tells a tale of what's to come
曇り空覗いた予感
Spread our wings with more courage than ever before
手を伸ばそう　いつよりも力強い勇気で
Light and dark are still vague in the distance
光も影もまだ遠くで
but still we want to know the reason behind kindness
それでも僕らは優しさの理由が知りたい
No one so far has ever reached
今は誰の名前でもない
the shining distance far beyond
輝きの彼方へ
Let's get there before the past takes it all
全部過去になる前に見つけに行こう
When the Fog Lifts
看到真面目
神山高校古典部は総勢四名
The Kamiyama High School Classics Club is four strong.
なぜ俺たちがこの路線バスに揺られているのか
So why are we letting this old bus shake our brains out?
それ　僕にも頂戴
Can I have some?
As you might imagine, it's more about the destination than the journey.
それは　当然このバスの行先と関係があるからだ
The Zaizen village is famous as a hiking spot and for its hot springs,
終点の財前村　登山と温泉で有名だ
and we're going there for the latter.
俺たちは登山ではなく温泉に向かっていた
夏休みならば休むのが生活信条に見合った行動だ　それなのに
My lifestyle dictates that I rest during summer break, and yet...
Thank you very much for helping find out what happened to my uncle!
叔父の件では　本当にありがとうございました折木さん
Now that we finally have the time, let's all go to the hot springs!
せっかくですので　皆さんで温泉に行きましょう
C'mon, let's go!
行きましょう　温泉
そう　だな
O... kay...
They should be here for us with a van...
もうじき迎えの番が来るはずなんだけど
やあ　いい景色だね
The scenery is really nice!
Um... Oreki?
あの折木さん　大丈夫ですか
Are you all right?
I feel sick...
酔った
これくらいで音を上げるとは　さすが奉太郎だ
I can't imagine anyone else getting motion sick so easily.
We were only on the road for an hour and a half. You're pathetic.
たった一時間半よ　だらしないわね
ところで摩耶花　よく宿が取れたね
By the way, Mayaka, how'd you find us a place to stay so easily?
My relatives run an inn in this area,
民宿を営んでる親戚が　いま建物が改装中でお客を取れられないからって
but they can't take guests now because they're renovating, so we get to use it for free.
無料で貸してくれたの
着きましたよ折木さん
We're there, Oreki.
All right! We made it!
やあ　着いた着いた
折木　早くしないと置いてくわよ
Oreki! Hurry up or you'll be left behind!
Greetings, dear inn! Well met!
やってきました僕らのお宿
Welcome to the Blue Mountain Inn!
いらっしゃいませ　青山荘へようこそ
Blue Mountain Inn
こっちが姉の善名梨絵で　こっちが妹の善名嘉代
This one's Zenna Rie,
and this is her little sister, Zenna Kayo.
こんにちは
Hi there!
小六と小四になったんだよね
They're in sixth and fourth grade now.
また背伸び…
You got taller ag—
Your rooms are at the end of the second floor!
お部屋は二階の奥だよ
Whoa! Hurry up, Houtarou!
奉太郎　速く速く
なかなか見晴らしのいい部屋だね
The view's not half bad from here.
I guess it's okay to do things like this every now and then.
たまにはこういうのも悪くない
Though, if I were up to me, I'd rather come alone.
まあ　贅沢を言えば一人で来る方が趣は深いだろうな
You? Traveling alone?
奉太郎が一人旅
冗談
No way.
Don't forget, the only reason we're here in the first place
千反田さんが企画して摩耶花がコネを使ったから
is because Chitanda planned it out and Mayaka used her connections.
ここにいるってことをお忘れなく
ごはんよ
Come and eat!
夕飯ですよ
Dinner is ready.
You heard it.
だってさ
Let's go!
行こうか
チーズか
Cheese?
シチュー　グラタン　チーズフォンデュ
Stew. Gratin. Cheese fondue.
Meat salad?
冷シャブ
せえの
One, two...
Let's eat!
いただきます
Save some room for dessert!
後でデザートもあるよ
Is it cheesecake?
チーズケーキか
何で分かったの
How did you know?
From the smell.
匂いがした
Amazing!
すごいな
Is it?
すごいか
摩耶姉ちゃんの言ってた通りだな
He's just like Mayaka said!
What did you tell them, Ibara?
何を言った伊原
明日みんなで花火しようよ
Let's all light fireworks tomorrow!
いいわね
Sounds good!
でしょう　昨日お父さんが買って…
I know, right? Dad bought some yest—
あんたなにやってんのよ
Aww, what're you doing?
ご　ごめんお姉ちゃん
S-Sorry!
Here.
はい
Thank you!
ありがとうございます
火傷してない
It didn't burn you?
It's okay.
大丈夫
Can't you be more careful?
もう　気を付けてよね
I couldn't eat another bite...
食った食った
里志の奴もう風呂に行ったのか
Satoshi went to take a bath already?
Well, I guess we did come all the way to the hot springs.
せっかく温泉宿に来たからな
Where are you off to, Oreki?
ところで折木さんはどちらまで
Same place as you.
お前と同じだ
Where's Ibara?
伊原は
子供たちに連れて行かれちゃいました
She went off with the girls.
This is a bit random, but what's your sister like?
突然なんですが　折木さんのお姉さんはどんな方ですか
That really is random.
本当に突然だな
That reminds me, aren't you an only child?
そう言えば千反田は一人っ子だったか
姉貴か
As for my sister...
いろんな意味で変わり者だし　いろんな意味で優秀だな
There's a fine line between genius and madness, and that describes her pretty well.
I don't think there's anything I could beat her at.
どうもあいつにはどの分野でも勝てる気がせん
ああ
Though, the thought of competing never even crossed my mind.
もっとも　勝ちたいと思ったこともないけどな
But why ask me about her all of a sudden?
で　なんでいきなり姉貴のことを
Did seeing the Zenna sisters remind you?
善名姉妹を見たからか
Actually,
実はですね　兄弟が欲しかったんです
I always wanted to have an older sister or a younger brother.
姉か弟　気の置けない相手がいつもそばにいるなんて
Wouldn't it be wonderful to have someone good-natured always close by?
素敵だと思いませんか
I beg to differ.
思いません
どうもお嬢様は人が良すぎる嫌いがある
Milady is far too good for this world, I fear.
If she pulled her head out of the clouds for one moment,
夢見過ぎじゃないか
兄弟なんて実際はまったく素敵ではないのだが
she'd realize brothers and sisters aren't all they're cracked up to be.
ここ　混浴じゃないようですね
Oh, this place doesn't have mixed bathing?
Why would it?
当たり前だ
里志か
Satoshi, huh?
お父さんお爺ちゃん　速く
Dad, Grandpa, hurry up!
もう
Whoa,
おお　案外広いな
it's a lot bigger than I expected.
Hey, Houtarou! Welcome to my domain!
やあ　奉太郎　来たね
This water is great! It washes you right through to your bones!
この湯はいいよ　体に染み透る
I'd rather not have bathwater mixing with my blood!
血液に水分が混じり合ったら危険だろ
くだらないこと言うね
That's not even funny.
まあ　リラックスしてる証拠なら結構なことだけど
Well, at least you're relaxing.
千反田か
Chitanda?
折木　どうしたの　大丈夫
Oreki!
What happened? Are you all right?
He just got dizzy from the heat.
湯あたりだよ
晕堂:因过度浸浴导致的不适
He's really outdone himself this time, I know.
情けないったらありゃしないよ
He hadn't been in for half the time I had,
僕の半分も入ってなかったくせに　気がついたら目をまわしてた
but before I knew it he'd almost passed out.
あんたってやつは
You're hopeless.
Sorry about that, guys...
悪いな　二人とも
Don't worry about it.
どういたしまして、だ
折木　あんたは結局イベントを楽しめない宿命なのね
I guess not being able to enjoy anything exciting is just your lot in life.
That's so true.
まったくだ
バス酔いが残ってたのかもな
Maybe it had something to do with my motion sickness earlier.
I feel sick.
気持ち悪い
Chitanda?
千反田か
Are you all right, Oreki?
折木さん　大丈夫ですか
Not really...
あんまり
You're still burning up.
まだ熱いですね
Should I bring you a wet towel?
タオルでも絞ってきましょうか
No...
いや　いらない
No thanks!
Um, I should sleep.
俺は寝る
せっかくの合宿に水を差して悪いな
Sorry to spoil your club trip.
Please don't say that.
そんなこと
We were thinking about getting together to tell ghost stories.
これから皆で怪談をしようって言ってるんですけど
もし体調が戻られたら　折木さんも来てくださいね
If you feel better, you should drop by.
Anyway, take care of yourself.
では　お大事に
Thanks...
ああ
It's not even eight o'clock yet.
まだ八時前か
太鼓
Drums?
本当は　わざわざ別館を建てなくてもやっていけたのよ
Actually, we didn't really need to build a second wing.
The other room's open too?
隣の部屋も空いてるのか
秘密があるの
There's a secret behind it.
A secret?
秘密って
A gloomy customer turned up once, a long time ago.
昔　陰気のお客さんが泊まりにきてね
本館の七号室にお通ししたんだけど
He stayed in room seven in the original wing.
食事はいらない　布団も敷かなくていい　とにかく近づくなって
He required neither food nor room service,
and told all the staff to stay away.
でも　前金払ってくれたし
But he paid in advance during a busy time, so it was convenient for them to let him stay.
忙しい時期だったからちょうどいいってなったんだって
However, that very night they heard a terrifying scream.
ところがその晩　すごい悲鳴が聞こえたの
A scream?
悲鳴
七号室に　首を吊った人影がぼうっと浮かび上がって
In room seven lay the grisly sight of a corpse hanging from the rafters,
swaying with macabre grace.
ゆらゆら揺れてたんだって
Apparently, the mysterious guest had stolen money from his employer and fled.
そのお客さん　会社のお金を使い込んで逃げて来たんだってさ
待ってました
I knew it!
やめなさいよ
Shut up!
そんなことがあってから　七号室に泊まったお客さんがね
Since then, many people who stayed in room seven
reported feeling as though something was there with them, like a lurking shadow.
この部屋には何かいる　夜中に影が浮かんでくるって
Then, the ninth person to stay there...
そして九人目に泊まったお客さんがね
どうされたんですか
What happened to him?
He suddenly took ill and died in the middle of the night!
夜のうちに　急な病気で死んじゃったの
No way!
そんな
そう来なくちゃ
Now you're talking!
やめなさいって
Oh, shut up!
だからおばあちゃん　お祓いを頼んで　さらにこの別館を建てたの
They called an exorcist and built the new wing of the building we're using now.
悪い噂が広がらないようにね
They had to stop the rumors from spreading.
So where's room seven?
その七号室って
It's over there in the old wing, right across from the window.
ほら　窓から見える真正面の　あの部屋よ
That room.
あたしたちは一階で暮らしてて
We live on the first floor there, and only go to the second floor when we have to.
二階にはあまり上がらないようにしてるの
Of course!
そうだね　冗談
小暑
大暑将至
But listen, you gotta keep this a secret!
いい　この話は絶対内緒よ
古風だ　実に
So old-style. So very old-style.
}立秋
初感秋意
Beginning of Autumn
When the first winds of autumn begin their journey.
Hyouka
Oh well...
朝か
Oh, good morning!
ああ　おはよう
おはよう　千反田たちは
Morning. Where are the girls?
I saw it...
出た
Saw what?
出たって何が
昨日夜中に　生あったかい風で目が覚めて
The creepy warm wind woke me up at night...
And when I tried to fall asleep again...
なんとなく寝返りうったら　向かいの部屋に首吊りの影が
I saw the shadow of a hanging man
swinging in the window of the room across from me!
ぼんやり浮かんで揺れてたの
狼狽える伊原もなかなか珍品だな
It's not often you see Ibara panic like this.
It's a shame Satoshi missed it.
これを見逃すとは里志も不運なやつだ
Thanks for the meal!
ご馳走さん
How was the bath?
露天風呂どうだった
It felt really good!
すごく気持ちよかったです
That's good to hear.
よかった
Rie
あと　お布団もふかふかだったでしょう
The mattresses were soft and fluffy too, right?
Yeah, I slept like a baby!
はい　よく眠れました
嘉代のはないみたいだな
I see there isn't one with Kayo's name.
Rie
摩耶姉ちゃんがああいう話苦手だったなんて知らなかったな
I didn't know you got scared so easily by ghost stories, Maya!
Ghosts don't scare me, okay?
あたしだって幽霊なら怖くないわよ
But I really saw that thing! I can't handle something that creepy!
でもあんなのまともに見たら
不気味にもほどがあるって
Maya... you really saw it?
摩耶姉ちゃん　見たの
I did, I did, I totally did!
見たわ絶対に見た本当に見た
Rie, did you tell them that story? Dad said not to tell anyone!
お姉ちゃん　あの話したの
お父さんがしちゃだめって言ってたのに
Oh shut up! It's just Maya, after all.
うるさいわね　いいじゃない摩耶姉ちゃんなんだし
What's wrong?
どうした
Um... What do you think of Mayaka's story?
あの　摩耶花さんのお話どう思いますか
首吊りの影か
About the hanging man's shadow?
Well, I guess ghosts could be kept in this world by their unfinished business...
まあ　定番やお約束ってのは
欠かせないから生き残ってるんだろう
So you think Mayaka's story could be true?
では折木さん　摩耶花さんの言うことが事実だと思いますか
I don't.
思わない
Then could my eyes have been playing tricks on me?
では　やっぱり思い違いでしょうか
ん　どういうことだ
How do you mean?
I saw it too.
私も見たんです　首吊りの影を
The hanging man's shadow.
Mayaka was moving about and she woke me up.
摩耶花さんが起きたので　私も目を覚ましたんです
I saw it swinging in the darkness.
そしたら　闇に浮かんで見えました
Oh.
I thought it was just my imagination,
思い違いかとも思ったのですが
摩耶花さんも同じものを見たと言うので
but if Mayaka saw the same thing as well...
You just saw what you wanted to see.
何かの見間違いだろう　昨日のあれだ
Like we said yesterday, "all ghosts are, when the fog lifts..."
幽霊の正体見たり
"...is withered grass in the wind"?
枯れ尾花ですか
だとしたら　何を見間違えたんでしょう
But if that's the case... What did I see?
That's right.
そうね　だったら何を見間違えたか言って見せてよ
If it wasn't a ghost, what did we see?
How would I—
何で俺が
Oreki!
折木さん　一緒に調べましょ
Let's find out together!
私　気になります
I can't stop thinking about it!
ごめん　ちーちゃん
I'm sorry, but I promised Rie I'd help her with her summer homework!
梨絵の夏休みの宿題見てあげる約束なの
任せてください
Leave it to us! We'll find the truth for sure!
私たちできっと真相を突き止めます
Is that okay, Oreki?
ね　折木さん
It's not okay at all.
「ね」と言われても
Anyway, what I have to do, I do quickly.
とにかく　やらなければいけない事は手短にだ
Excuse me!
お邪魔します
さて　その影とやらはお前の部屋の真向かいに見えたのか
Well then. You said you saw the shadow in the room across from yours?
ええ　そうでした
Yes.
How big was it?
大きさは？
I wouldn't say it was particularly big or small.
大きすぎも小さすぎもしなかったと思います
What shape?
形は？
I don't really remember.
よく覚えていないんです
What color?
色は？
I don't know. It was a shadow...
わかりません　影だったので
影か
A shadow, huh?
So you saw someone's shadow, lit from behind.
つまり逆光だったから　人の姿が影になって見えたってことか
I think so.
そうだと思います
Lit from behind, huh...
逆光ねえ
At night, the Moon would be the most likely light source.
夜の光源っていえば　まあ　月だろうが
That sounds right.
私もそう思います
The Moon was quite bright last night.
昨日の晩月は随分明るかったかと
But why does that—
それが何か？
Chitanda, around when did you finish telling ghost stories and go to bed?
千反田　怪談が終わって寝たのは何時だ
Um, about ten o'clock.
えっと　十時です
そのとき雨戸は？
Was the window open?
閉まっていたと思います
It was closed, I think.
There's no way you could see a shadow through the storm shutters.
雨戸が閉まっているかぎり　影はできない
This is getting complicated.
厄介なことになってきた
I guess we should go check out room seven for ourselves.
こうなったら　本館七号室を見たほうがいいだろう
That's wonderful! So mysterious!
いいですね　謎めいて
I'm glad we came on this trip!
やっぱり合宿を開いてよかったです
開かなくてよかったです
I could've lived without it.
No entry
Hey!
なあ
Wh-What is it?
はい　なんですか
Please.
頼む　子供は苦手だ
I can't handle kids.
Of course.
はい　嘉代さん　ちょっといいですか
Kayo, do you have a moment?
We'd like to go to the old wing.
私たち本館に入りたいんですけど
The old wing? Why?
本館に？　どうしてですか
We're investigating that hanging shadow,
例の首吊りの影のことを調べているんです
so we wanted to take a look at room seven.
七号室を見せていただきたいんですが
Sorry, you can't go there now.
ごめんなさい　今はだめなんです
Rie would get mad at me.
お姉ちゃんに怒られちゃう
Then just tell us one thing.
じゃあ　一つ教えてくれ
あの部屋はいまでも客室なのか
Do people still stay in that room?
No. In the old wing only the bath and the dining room are open to guests.
違います　本館はお客さん用にはお風呂場と食堂しか使っていません
Then it's empty?
じゃあ　空き部屋か
二階は全部物置になっています
The second floor rooms are all used for storage.
Can I go?
もういいですか
Thanks! You really helped...
ありがとう　役に立った…
She hates me.
嫌われたな
Don't worry about it.
いいじゃないですか　大きな男の人が怖いんでしょう
Talking to a big guy like you must be scary for her.
かわいいですよ
It's pretty cute.
Is it a problem if we can't look at room seven?
七号室に入れないと困りますか
困るというより面倒になった　現場検証ができないからな
Not really, but it makes things more difficult,
since we can't investigate the scene.
Ah, this brings back memories.
あら　懐かしいものがありますね
Rie
朝のラジオ体操
Reminds me of morning exercises on the radio.
一昨年までは通っていました
I did them until a couple of years ago.
中学二年まで　本当に
Until the middle of junior high? Seriously?
Let's check the back of the building too.
裏手からも見てみましょう
昨日の晩雨は降ったか
Did it rain last night?
Yeah, a little.
ええ　一雨
You'd need the shutters on both the east and west side to be open to see a shadow lit from behind.
影を浮びあがらせるには
西側と東側の両方の雨戸を開けねばならないというわけだ
あのう
Um...
Lunch is ready.
お昼ごはんです
Thanks for the meal!
ご馳走様
やっぱりいいですねえ　姉妹って
It really is great having a sister, isn't it?
Oh? You want a sister of your own, Chitanda?
へえ　千反田さんは姉妹に憧れでも？
Kind of.
ええ　ちょっと
Did you find anything out?
で　何かわかった？
No, not yet.
いいえ
We just investigated the scene.
まだ下調べだ　仮説はあるがな
I have a theory, though.
へえ　聞かせてよ
Oh? What is it?
え？
So, um...
あのさ　一体何の相談
what exactly are you talking about?
I don't like being out of the loop.
僕をかやの外にするなんて
かやの外も何もお前いつもどこに行ってるんだ
Since when have you tried to be in the loop?
You've hardly been around.
全然見ないぞ
You don't get it, do you?
わかってないなあ　温泉は何度でも浸かりに行くのが作法だよ
What's the point of hot springs if you don't use them?
I guess...
そんなものかね
じゃん～　どう？　あたしの浴衣
Ta-da!
Well? How's my yukata?
It's pretty!
素敵ですね
It's nice!
いいじゃない
I finally got one at the start of summer break!
夏休みの初めにやっと買ってもらったんだ
ずっとほしいって言ってたもんね
You've wanted one for ages, right?
趣味はいいね
I guess it's good for what it is.
What's wrong with it?
何がよくない
Take a look at the sash.
あの帯さ　イミテーションじゃないか
It's an imitation.
It doesn't look different to me.
何が突然変異だ？
Not "mutation". Imitation.
ミューテーションじゃない　イミテーションだよ
The bow is pre-made, so they just add it on.
結び目だけ別に用意したものをとりつけるのさ
I wouldn't consider that a real yukata.
僕はあれを浴衣とは認めない
That's stupid.
ばかばかしい
What's the matter?
どうかしたかい
Oh? So now I'm also being haunted by the hanging man's shadow?
さては俺も首吊りの影の呪いにかかったか
Let's go to the hot spring we went to yesterday.
昨日の温泉に行こう
Okay!
はい
The hanging man's shadow
首吊りの影　それは伊原と千反田の錯覚の産物　枯れ尾花だ
is simply the product of Ibara and Chitanda's imagination.
It's just withered grass in the wind.
But there's still something missing.
しかし　もう一押し足りない
Let's go back together afterward, okay?
一緒に出ましょうね
Satoshi, huh?
里志か
You were sitting at the lunch table when we left!
お前　さっきまで食事の席にいただろ
How did you get here already?
一体いつの間に来たんだ
If you slide down the cliff behind the inn, you end up right here at the hot springs.
やあ　青山荘の裏手の崖を滑り降りるとこの真裏に出るんだよ
He slid down the cliff just to take a shortcut?
たかが近道のために崖を滑り降りるとは　里志らしい
That's exactly the kind of thing he'd do.
I can't think of an explanation that'd satisfy Chitanda.
千反田を満足させられる説明がつかない
Figuring out where the shadow came from was the easy part.
影の正体は難しくない
The question is, why would they do that?
要はなぜそうしたのかということだ
What's up, Houtarou? Did the heat overload your brain again?
奉太郎　まさかのぼせたのかい
なあ　昨日の晩何かイベントはなかったか
Did anything noteworthy happen last night?
Well, you passed out in the bath, for one.
湯あたりした奉太郎
Not that!
じゃなくて
ああ　みんなで怪談話をした
We told ghost stories.
I had more girls around me than I knew what to do with!
両手に花でも一輪余ったよ
いや　もっとオフィシャルなやつだ
No, something more official!
Oh right, there was a summer festival.
そいや　夏祭りがあったよ
Couldn't you hear the drums?
太鼓の音が聞こえてたじゃない
Drums?
太鼓
I see!
そうか　夏祭り
The summer festival!
So that's it.
なるほど
Why do you ask?
で　それが何か？
首吊りの影　あれな
The hanging man's shadow...
I think it was a yukata hung up by the window.
ハンガーにかかった浴衣だったんだろうな
Why would someone hang up a yukata there?
なんでそんなところに浴衣が
And why would they open the shutters just to show it to us? It doesn't make sense!
それに　雨戸を開けてまで私たちに浴衣の影を見せるなんて変です
They didn't do that to show it to you.
お前たちに見せるためじゃない
Then?
じゃあ
She was drying it.
乾かしていたんだよ　濡れた浴衣を
Her wet yukata.
She opened the shutters to let the wind through so it'd dry faster.
雨戸が開いてたのは風通しをよくして早く乾かすため
なんで
But why?
It rained.
雨が降ったから
That's not what I meant. Why room seven?
違います　何で七号室なんですか
乾かしているところを見られないようにするためだ
So that no one would see her drying it.
But we saw it.
私たち見ました
No,
違う　家族から隠したかったんだ
she wanted to hide it from her family.
どうして
Why?
Kayo was drying the yukata.
浴衣を干したのは嘉代だ
嘉代は梨絵の浴衣が羨ましく　着てみたいと思った
She was envious of Rie's yukata and wanted to try it on.
But Rie wouldn't lend it to her.
でも　梨絵は貸してくれないだろう
Why not? They're sisters!
どうしてですか　姉妹ですよ
気付かなかったか
Didn't you notice?
梨絵は湯飲みもラジオ体操のカードもボールも
Her mug, her exercise stamp sheet, her ball...
Rie makes it clear what's hers.
自分のものははっきりと区別している子なんだ
She couldn't ask Rie to lend it to her.
そんな梨絵に「浴衣を貸して」なんて言えなかったんだ
そんな
But...
But Kayo wanted to try it on,
だが嘉代は着たかった
so she nicked it to wear to the summer festival last night.
だから持ち出して　昨日の夏祭りにそれを着ていった
It was at eight o'clock.
時刻は八時
Kayo went to the festival?
嘉代さんが夏祭りに？
見たんだよ
I saw someone leave the house at eight last night.
昨日の夜八時に家を出ていく人影を
嘉代は怪談話の場にはいなかったようだな
Kayo wasn't there when you were telling ghost stories, was she?
No, she wasn't.
確かに嘉代さんはいませんでした
Then, as Kayo was having fun at the festival, disaster struck.
そんなとき　祭りを楽しむ嘉代に不幸が起きた
It rained.
雨が降った
It didn't rain for long, but the yukata was soaked.
雨はすぐにあがったが　浴衣は濡れた
Then she remembered tomorrow's fireworks.
嘉代は明日の花火の予定を思い出した
Rie would definitely want to wear her yukata then.
梨絵は間違いなくこの浴衣を着て　花火をしたがるだろう
And if she couldn't get it dry by then, Rie would kill her.
なんとか明日までに浴衣を乾かさないと　梨絵に責められる
If she hung it up on the first floor of the old wing, her family would find it.
本館の一階は家族に見つかる　別館は論外
The new wing would be out of question,
and there's no way she could use the dryers unnoticed.
夜中に乾燥機は使えない
So she waited until everyone fell asleep,
だから　嘉代はみんなが寝静まる頃を見計らって
and hung the yukata in the room at the end of the old wing's second floor.
本館二階の一番奥の部屋に浴衣を干した
更に嘉代の不幸は続く
But further misfortune would befall her.
開いた窓から月明かりが差し込み　首吊りの影を見せた
The moonlight shone through the open windows and revealed the hanging man's shadow.
And her final piece of bad luck was that we started investigating that shadow.
そして最後の不幸は　俺たちが首吊りの影を調べたこと
She must've felt like she was walking on hot coals.
嘉代は針の筵だったはずだ
I bet that shadow back then was Kayo as well.
おそらくあのときのふすまの人影は嘉代だったに違いない
Kayo...
嘉代さん
She returned the yukata early in the morning.
浴衣は朝早くに戻しておいた
Unlike Rie, Kayo does morning exercises every day.
梨絵と違って毎日ラジオ体操に通ってる嘉代のことだ
Returning it would have been simple.
戻すのは簡単だっただろう
そうでしたか
I see.
Let's keep this a secret from Ibara.
このことは伊原にはふせておく
色々事情ってものもあるだろうからな
Families are complicated, after all.
But then...
そうなら　あの二人は仲が悪いということになります
Those two don't get along very well.
They're sisters, but they can't even lend their clothes to each other...
浴衣を貸し借りすることもできない姉妹なんて
That's pretty normal for siblings.
そんなもんじゃないか　兄弟なんて
I always wanted one of my own.
私は兄弟がほしかったんです
尊敬できる姉か　可愛い弟か
An older sister I could respect, or a cute little brother.
I guess the brother or sister that Chitanda wished she could have
千反田の望む兄弟ってのは
枯れ尾花なのかもな
was, in the end, just withered grass in the wind.
It's still boiling...
暑っ
You okay?
いける？
うん
Or maybe there's more to it than that.
まあ　枯れ尾花ばかりでもないかもな
今夜恋に変わる　幸せな夢で会おう
Let us meet in a blissful dream tonight, let it be our love
きっと　ねぇ見つけてね
Find me, I beg you
まどろみの約束
We promised to meet, drifting in and out of sleep
芽生えてた温もり　暖かくて戸惑う
This sprouting warmth confuses us
こんな気持ちをまだ　あなたは分からないよ
Don't you understand this feeling yet?
そんな視線には意味なんて　別にないはず
Normally such random glances hold no meaning
だって友達にしてるのと同じ
Isn't it the same when making friends?
明け方に消えてく　小さな願星
The little shooting stars we wish upon, vanishing into the dawn
夜の間だけの魔法を…
are a magic that only unfolds in the night
今夜恋に変わる　幸せな夢で会おう
Let us meet in a blissful dream tonight, let it be our love
きっと　ねぇ見つけてね
Find me, I beg you
まどろみの約束
We promised to meet, drifting in and out of sleep
Next time: To the Preview!
次回　試写会に行こう
To the Preview!